Listen to a talk in an anthropology class.
Man:
In the first half of the 20th century, an anthropological movement emerged, called the Culture and Personality School.
According to the Culture and Personality school, people's personalities are a result of the
culture they live in,
and not just based on biology, like not just inherited from their biological parents.
For example, how children in a culture experience food, the foods they eat, how
it's prepared, this shapes their individual tastes and preferences.
One of the anthropologists most associated with this movement was Ruth Benedict.
Benedict studied and embraced the principles of cultural relativism.
So according to cultural relativism, all cultures should be studied on their own terms
and not judged against some external measure.
So cultures in, say, Egypt, belong to Egypt and shouldn't be the standard of
what all cultures should try to be.
Ruth Benedict refuted the dominant anthropology theory at the time,
which stated that there was a hierarchy of cultures, some advanced, others not.
Rejecting that took courage.
And I think the field is better for it.
Benedict was also influenced by psychology, especially Gestalt ideas.
According to Gestalt psychology, a personality is an integrated whole, not just a list of traits.
Like, If you see a painting of a landscape, you're looking at a whole landscape
and not just say, a hill, trees and a farmhouse.
Benedict said that cultures were the same way, a whole coherent system with patterns of values
and behaviors,
and more than just a set of characteristics.